

PROFILE

As a student at the faculty of Mechanical Engineering, I am motivated to learn new things and gain new experiences. Thereby my interests lie in research and development.

My personal interests are determined by a sporty and ecological lifestyle.

Furthermore, my hobbies include working on technical projects, such as the independent learning of programming languages for web development and electrical engineering projects with the Raspberry Pi and Arduino.

CONTACT

Phone:

(+49) 17630170857

E-Mail:

Vanessa.rathke@gmail.com

Webpage:

https://vanessarathke.github.io/Vanessa Rathke/

HOBBIES

Electrotechnical projects Webdevelopment Horse riding

VANESSA RATHKE

EDUCATION

HTWG Konstanz: Process and environmental technology (B.SC.) 2020 - today

Seoul National University of Science and Technology, South Korea September – December 2021

HTWG Konstanz: Environmental technology and resource management 2018 - 2020

German high school: Friedrich-Wöhler-Gymnasium, Singen 2009 - 2017

WORKING EXPERIENCE

Mercedes-Benz AG: Internship in System Concepts and Realization September 2022 – today

In the field of R&D the following work is done: prototyping, construction, electrotechnical projects.

Miltenyi Imaging GmbH: Working student in production transition October 2020 – April 2021

The activity included the coordination of project implementation in the area of production transition with regard to the topic of digitalization 4.0.

RBR Elektroteam GdbR: Internship in electrics and construction August – September 2019

ACS Umwelttechnik: Internship in environmental technology July – August 2019

The project WavE-Project Hypowave: Use of hydroponic systems for resource-efficient agricultural water reuse was supported.

SKILLS

Languages

German (native) French (B1) English (fluently, B2/C1) Italian (B1)

Computer skills

FEA: Ansys (CFD, CFX) MS Office CAD: Solidworks, Siemens NX C++, HTML, CSS

Matlab, Simulink

Miscellaneous

Technical drawing Testing experience

VOLUNTARY ACTIVITIES

University of Konstanz: MINT & Me Mentoring

March 2021 - today

The mentor supports female students in their choice of studies.

University of Konstanz: eLaketric Racing Team

March – September 2022

The team develops a racing motorcycle for the MotoStudent competition

University of Konstanz: Helping Hand

December 2020 - July 2022

International students at the university are supported.